(English Subtitle) Growing.Pains.S01E12 -= A.Christmas.Story =- Subripped by zerox
我的圣人呢？
Where are my wise men?
坐火车去了
Taking the A train.
迈克，他怎么坐到车轨上了？
Mike, what are the wise men doing on the train track?
他们是圣人，自有圣人之道
Hey, they're wise men. They must know what they're doing.
导演：约翰.特莱西
麦克，够了
Mike, come on.
奇迹啊
It's a miracle.
麦克
Mike.
★我们三个国王都喜欢.
We three kings We know what we like
★兴麦克一起过圣诞
Spending Christmas With our friend Mike
本，够了!
Ben, stop that.
饭后再拆礼物
You'll get to open one present after dinner.
你说过每个人都会有一份.
But I thought you said everyone's Christmas-Eve present...
绑着红色大蝴蝶结的礼物的
would have a big, red bow on it.
会有的
It will.
就我没有
Well, everyone has one with a big, red bow on it except me.
也许我们应该说出真相
Well, maybe we should tell him the truth, guys.
真相？
What truth?
本，你是领养来的
Well, Ben, you're adopted...
圣诞老人不知道你的新地址
and Santa doesn't know your new address.
-妈妈! -麦克
- Mom! - Mike.
只有麦克才是领养的
The only one of us kids who's adopted is Mike.
我不是领养的
I'm not adopted.
快了
Not yet.
我的礼物确实不在那里
My present's definitely not here.
也许圣诞老人还没有买你的礼物
Well, Ben, maybe Santa just hasn't brought it yet.
拜托，世上哪有圣诞老人
Come on. There's no such thing as Santa.
本，你怎么知道没有呢？
Hey, Ben, you know that for a fact?
好吧，好吧，听我说.
Okay. Okay, I tell you what.
我现在就去吃饼干
I'll go get myself some Christmas cookies, and who knows?
或许圣诞老人会认为 这是送我礼物的最佳时机
Maybe Santa will decide this is the perfect opportunity to bring my present.
懂我意思吗？
Know what I mean?
你们要几点去拿礼物？
So, when are you guys gonna pick it up?
四点钟左右
Around 4:00.
他到时一定会很开心
He's gonna be so excited.
杰森，我的礼物会让我开心吗？
So, Jason, how excited am I gonna be about my present?
那就要看你乖不乖，顽不顽皮
Well, that depends. Have you been naughty, or have you been nice?
我又顽皮又乖
I've been nice and naughty.
圣诞老人就喜欢你这样
Santa likes it when you talk like that.
-大家快来!下雪了 -好啊!
- Hey, everybody! It's snowing. - Oh, all right!
-白色的圣诞节! -瞧瞧!
- All right, on Christmas! - Oh, yeah! Look at that.
真漂亮
Oh, it's beautiful.
圣诞节真温馨.
You know, Christmas is sort of neat...
一家五口，济济一堂
I mean, just the five of us hanging out...
漂亮，温暖的家，真有气氛
in a nice, warm house, kind of getting into the spirit.
-麦克？ -麦克？
- Mike? - Mike?
你们以为我只会招人讨厌吗？
Hey, you think I like being obnoxious all the time?
对，我确实如此
Yeah, I guess I do.
我去开门
I'll get it.
有这么一个孩子真是三生有幸
What did we do to be blessed with such a child?
爸，有病人来了
Dad, it's one of your patients.
波德维尔先生!这装扮不错
Mr. Bodewell! I think the suit looks great.
医生，我们得聊聊
I gotta talk to you, Doc.
你不是要去孤儿院做圣诞老人吗？
Aren't you supposed to be playing Santa down at the orphanage?
-我演不下去了 -为什么？
- I can't go through with that. - Why not?
瞧我的
Watch this.
呵呵
Ho, ho.
咱来聊聊
Let's talk.
波德维尔，上周的你为了.
Walter, when I saw you last week...
能在孤儿院做圣诞老人 而感到兴高采烈
you were so excited about playing Santa for those kids at the orphanage.
后来怎么了？
What happened?
医生，孩子们一定会讨厌我
Doc, the kids are gonna hate me.
为什么会讨厌你？
Now, why should they hate you?
就像大家讨厌我一样
Same reason everybody hates me.
我让大家都不愉快
I make people uncomfortable.
瞧，你开始坐立不安了
Look at you. You're fidgeting.
我没有坐立不安
I'm not fidgeting.
好了，你一辈子最害怕的是什么？
Okay, now, Walter, what's the one thing in your life that bothers you the most?
杂志上掉下来的订阅卡
Those little subscription cards that fall out of magazines.
波德维尔.
Walter.
-最害怕寂寞 -是的
- Being alone. - Yes.
你不觉得孤儿院的孩子们很寂寞吗？
And don't you think those kids at the orphanage are lonely, too?
是的，但是我不知道怎么跟孩子们说话
Yeah, but I don't know how to talk to kids, Doc.
放松吧，你会知道该说什么
Well, relax. Just be yourself. You'll know what to say.
我确实有些话要说
Well, I've been kicking around a few things.
很好，假设你走进孤儿院
Good. Imagine you've just come into the orphanage...
身边都是快活的小脸蛋
and you're surrounded by all those happy little faces...
你会说些什么？
and what do you say?
“敬启者..”
"To whom it may concern...
“适才忽觉明日乃圣诞良辰”
"it has come to my attention that tomorrow is Christmas.
“故略备薄礼，聊表祝贺..”
"Consequently, I bring items in conjunction with..."
作为一名会计 你有时候未免倾向于.
Walter, I wonder if, as an accountant, you might have a tendency to be...
我知道，太正式了
I know, I know. Too formal.
波德维尔 圣诞老人很少说这样的话
Walter, I don't know that that much talk is expected of Santa.
也许该传统一点
I might just go with something more traditional.
例如：“呵呵呵!孩子们，礼物来了!”
You know, like, "Ho! Ho! Ho! Boy, do I have gifts for you!"
显然你做过儿童工作
You have obviously worked with children.
你也会很好的
Come on, Walter. You'll be fine.
我还不知道礼物对不对呢
Oh, Doc, I don't even know if I brought the right gifts.
孩子们什么礼物都喜欢
You can't go wrong with kids. They love gifts.
这是什么？
See what you got here.
碎牛肉？
Ground beef?
有话就说吧
Go ahead. Say it.
早知道就买猪肉
I should've bought pork.
就差这么一点
Well, that's a close call, Walter.
好，还有些什么
Come on. What else have you got?
厨房用品
Tupperware.
这是兴牛肉配套的
Sure, I thought it goes with the beef.
用来放牛肉丸
You know, they'll use it to mix up some Swedish meatballs or...
买错礼物了
The gifts are wrong.
医生，我想要让孩子们开心的礼物
Doc, I wanna give these kids something that's gonna make them happy...
不知道送什么好
but I don't know what to bring.
我说送些没用的东西吧
Walter, I'm gonna throw out something kind of crazy now.
玩具
Toys.
玩具？
Toys?
玩具
Toys.
玩具确实没用，但也许合适
Doc, that is so crazy, that just might work.
戴上吧
Here.
不用骗我了，你们去拿礼物吧？
You guys can't fool me. You're going to get my present.
-哪里？我们是去… -找铁匠，凯罗要换双鞋子
- Nonsense, Ben, we're going to the... - Blacksmith. Carol needs new shoes.
我们要去退掉麦克的礼物
Actually, we're going to return all of Mike's gifts.
-他的车匙给你了 -好啊你们
- You take his Porsche. - What? Oh, you guys.
算了，告诉我是什么礼物吧
Come on. Just tell me what my present is.
这是你和圣诞老人的事情
That's between you and Santa.
我现在越来越讨厌 这个传说中的人物了
I'm getting pretty sick of this particular folk hero.
-别那么大声 -再见
- I wouldn't say that too loudly. - Bye, guys.
-再见 -再见
- All right, bye-bye. - Bye.
-祝你愉快 -再见
- Have fun. - See you later.
麦克，凯罗
Mike, Carol.
凯罗，麦克.. 知道圣诞节要怎样吗？
Carol, Mike. Do you know what Christmas means to me?
要互助互爱，坦诚相见
It means caring, sharing.
-本，我们不会告诉你的 -本，我们不会告诉你的
- We're not telling you, Ben. - We're not telling you, Ben.
我喜欢你的架势
But I like your style.
这种要问谁才能知道呢？
Who do you have to talk to to get some hard facts around here?
你该找一个穿红衣服的胖子
Well, I'd look for a fat man in a red suit.
-波德维尔先生 -你父亲在否？
- Mr. Bodewell. - Is your father here?
-不在，刚出去了 -进来等吧
- No, he stepped out for a minute. - Would you like to come in and wait?
不，等不了啦
No, I can't wait.
那我告诉他，你曾来过 圣诞快乐!
Okay, I'll tell him you were here. Merry Christmas!
他一点都不快乐
He sure looked unhappy.
麦克，凯罗 凯罗，麦克
Mike, Carol. Carol, Mike.
谁告诉我给他1块钱
$1 for the hiding place.
本，这有违圣诞精神
Ben, that's hardly the Christmas spirit.
10块钱呢？
$10?
★叮叮当，叮叮当.
Jingle bells, jingle bells
我不会说的，起码要20块嘛
I wasn't going to tell him, not for less than $20.
谁在上面？
Who is up there?
你说呢？
Who do you think?
哇!
Whoa!
圣诞老人？
Santa?
圣诞老人!难以置信!
Santa Claus! Wow, this is unbelievable!
小子走开，我要跳下来 不想让你看见
Get out of there, kid. Look, I'm coming down. I don't want you to see this.
方便的话，把礼物扔下来吧
Well, if it's any easier for you, you can throw my present down.
礼物？好的，送你一份
Present? Oh, okay, I'll give you a present.
生牛肉？
Raw meat?
不好吗？
You got a problem with that?
我想要的不是这个
Well, it wasn't my first choice.
圣诞节前夜，好吃的东西真多
Christmas Eve, a real "stuff your face" kind of holiday.
本，过来吃鸡蛋卷
Come on, Ben. Let's have some eggnog.
麦克!凯罗，圣诞老人在屋顶上 瞧他送我的礼物
Mike! Carol! Santa's on the roof, and look what he gave me.
生牛肉？什么天方夜谭？
Raw meat? Ben, what are you talking about?
快来
Come on.
圣诞老人，我哥哥姐姐来了 有礼物吗？
Santa, my brother and sister are here. You got anything for them?
厨房用品？
Tupperware?
这是送给那位小姐的
Oh, it's for the young lady.
请让开
Would you please get out of there?
波德维尔先生？
Mr. Bodewell?
是的
You got it.
你在上面干什么？
Mr. Bodewell, what are you doing up there?
我要从你们家烟囱跳下来，插水式
I'm gonna dive down your chimney, head first.
天哪，他要自杀
Oh, my God. He's going to commit suicide in our fireplace.
好吧，我去叫警察
Okay, I'm gonna call the cops.
不，别叫警察
No, no cops.
我没说叫“警察”
Okay, I didn't say "cops."
我是说“请喝茶”
I said "mops."
不用喝茶了
Yeah, well, no mops, either.
好的，免茶水
Right, no mops.
什么都不喝
Right, or cleaning supplies of any kind.
波德维尔先生，先别动
Mr. Bodewell, just stay where you are.
我马上回来，你们要一直跟他谈话
I'll be right back. I think you're supposed to keep him talking.
跳下来以后继续谈？
Even after he jumps?
下来吃点鸡蛋卷吗？
Mr. Bodewell, why don't you come down and have some eggnog?
我都要死了，还吃什么鸡蛋卷？
I'm about to kill myself, you offer me eggnog?
上面写着“适合任何场合食用”
Well, it says here, "Festive for all occasions."
你真行
Oh, Mike.
本，到你了
Okay. Ben, your turn.
波德维尔先生 谢谢你送我的生牛肉
Mr. Bodewell, even though you're not Santa, thank you for the meat.
明年肯定用得着
I know I'll use it for years to come.
你还是坦白说出来吧 你不喜欢这块肉
Come on, kid. Admit it. You hate the meat.
不，你让我美梦成真了
No, really, it's a child's dream come true.
嘴巴真甜，可是瞒不过我
Nice try, kid, but I know the truth.
你其实讨厌我
You hate me.
大家都讨厌我!
Everybody! Everybody hates me!
所以我活不下去了
That's why I can't go on living.
人总得活下去
But you have to go on living.
-为什么？ -等等，我来告诉你
- Why? - Wait a second. I'll tell you.
-什么东西？ -爸爸的教科书
- Hey, what's that? - One of Dad's textbooks.
波德维尔先生，“一个想自杀的人..”
Mr. Bodewell, I know that "a suicidal person"...
“例如阁下..”
such as yourself...
“他们只会通过黑暗的管道来看世界”
"can only see things through a dark tunnel...
“但通过交谈和长期资料后..”
"but with proper counseling and long-term therapy...
“病人会建立内在的自信 详看费博的名著..”
"the patient can build his inner confidence, as outlined in Ferber's landmark study...
“”
"Life Without Hope."
波德维尔先生？
Mr. Bodewell?
还在吗？
Mr. Bodewell, are you there?
我在，你还没念完吧？
Yeah, sure. I didn't think you were finished reading.
千万别跳下来
Mr. Bodewell, please don't jump.
★圣诞老人来了.
Here comes Santa Claus
Here comes Santa Claus Right down
从屋顶上来!
Right down our chimney!
什么？
What?
波德维尔先生在屋顶，他要跳下来!
Mr. Bodewell's on the roof, and he's about to jump down the chimney!
天哪!
Oh, my God!
波德维尔先生？
Mr. Bodewell?
-波德维尔 -医生，别过来
- Walter. - Don't come near me, Doc.
我发誓我要跳了
I swear I'll dive.
别着急，我不过来 只是想聊聊
Okay, don't worry. I'll stay right here. I just wanna talk to you.
我不要谈，我要死
Well, I don't wanna talk. I wanna die.
你的问题是暂时性的
Walter, your problems are temporary.
而死是永恒的
Death is permanent.
跳下去就没第二次了.. 你在干什么？
You jump, and there's no second... Walter, what are you doing?
量一下尺寸够不够
I want to make sure I'm gonna fit.
卡在中间那才叫惨哪
I'll be damned if I'm gonna get stuck in there.
今天下午是怎么了？
What happened this afternoon?
孤儿院的孩子们都讨厌我
The kids at the orphanage hated me.
竟然有这种事情？
Well, I find that hard to believe, Walter.
给8，9岁的孩子办圣诞老人？
I mean, you played Santa to a bunch of 8-year-olds.
是不是你误解了？
Could it be that you misinterpreted their response?
你自己看吧
You tell me.
“这个圣诞老人是疯子”
"This Santa eats fruitcake."
对，屋顶上有个人要跳下来
That's right. A man on the roof, threatening to jump down the chimney.
是的，很胖，花白胡子，一身红衣服
Well, he's a rather large man in a red suit, with a white beard.
不，他没有驯鹿和拉车
No, he doesn't have any reindeer.
我了解你心中郁闷.
Walter, I understand what you're going through.
此刻心灰意冷，可是也不能这样
Things look bleak for you right now, but you can't do this.
你说得对
You're right.
穿这件衣服是跳不下去的
Not with this jacket on. I'm never gonna fit.
-生命诚可贵 -别过来
- Walter, your life is too valuable. - Don't come near me.
面对现实吧，我这辈子是白过了
Let's face it, Doc. My life is a big zero.
一天天这样过又何苦呢？
I wake up every day, and I'm wondering why.
把腰围除以3.14.
Divide the circumference by pi...
为什么？偏偏是我？
Why? Why me?
为什么我是波德维尔？ 既然命该如此
Why was I chosen to be Walter Bodewell, the man whose destiny was to...
该死，电池没电了
Damn, my batteries are dead.
医生，可以问你一个问题吗？
Doc, would you please tell me one thing?
-问吧？ -39除以3.14159是多少？
- What, Walter? - What's 39 divided by 3.1416?
我不会帮你算这个的
Walter, I'm not gonna help you with this.
那好，随你
Oh, well, fine. Have it your way.
波德维尔
Walter.
波德维尔!
Walter!
这样一了百了.
Walter, you wanna be happy.
不能解决问题
You don't wanna give up like this.
为什么不能？
Why shouldn't I? Huh, Doc?
你说，为什么不能？
You tell me. Why shouldn't I give up?
既然在8，9岁的孩子们前面 都当不好圣诞老人
I mean, if I can't make it as Santa Claus with a bunch of 8-year-old orphans...
我又怎么能当好波德维尔？
how am I supposed to make it as Walter Bodewell?
你试试看.
Well, you work at it, Walter.
一个个问题地解决
You chip away at each problem.
扪心自问.
You speak from the heart...
偶尔不用写发言稿
occasionally without a prepared statement.
慢慢的.
And then, when you listen back...
你就会像大家一样
you know, you start to sound just like everybody else.
一切很正常
You're human, Walter.
每一个人也会偶尔神伤.
That means occasionally you're gonna have some pain...
偶尔寂寞
and sometimes you're gonna feel lonely...
可是若能伸出手来.
but if you just keep reaching out...
总会有人愿、意拉你一把
there's gonna be somebody there to lend you a hand.
谢谢你，医生，永别了
Thanks, Doc. Goodbye.
波德维尔!
Walter!
-什么？ -我想通了
对了!
Oh, that's it. That's it!
你说得对!
- What's it? - I see it now.
我也要自杀，碰到问题.
Yeah, this is a good idea, Walter.
I'm gonna kill myself, too. That's it. You just have a problem...
跳烟囱就得了
and you jump down the chimney, Walter.
-你不能 -为什么不能？这是我家的烟囱
- No, you can't do that. - Why not, Walter? It's my chimney.
你胡说什么了？
What are you talking about?
你以为只有你有问题吗？
Walter, you think you're the only one with problems?
我也有.
Well, I got a problem, too, Walter...
因为我有个病人在屋顶上扬言要自杀
'cause I got a big guy on my roof I've been counseling for four years...
这个病人我已经治疗4年了 徒劳无功
and he's threatening to kill himself because I can't talk him out of it.
我受到自己的良心责备啊!
I can't live with that on my conscience, Walter.
-不，不! -不好意思，我先
- No. No! - Excuse me. You mind if I go first?
医生，你不能这样
Doc, I'm not gonna let you do this.
你还有老婆孩子
You have a wife. You have children.
没有我，他们的圣诞节还是好好的
Their Christmas is pretty much shot as it is.
别拦着我
你疯了？
You are crazy!
医生，我不能让你去死
Don't try to stop me, Walter.
No, Doc, I can't let you do this!
医生，别哭了，可怜兮兮的
Doc, quit whining. It's really pathetic.
-我可没哭 -那是谁？
- It's not me. - Well, what is it?
你给儿子送了条小狗？
So you bought a puppy for your kid for Christmas?
他一直渴望有一条小狗
He's been asking for one for years, so...
-被他提前发现了 -是啊
- I guess he found it a little early. - Yeah.
棕色的
这狗是什么样子的？
What kind of puppy is it?
Brown.
它在干什么？
What is he doing?
在舔我的脸
Licking my face.
-本，你在干嘛.. -我以前养过小狗
- Ben, what are you... - I used to have a dog.
德国牧羊犬
I had a German Shepherd.
听话
那条狗听话吗？
Was he a nice dog?
Yeah.
它是唯一.
He was the only guy...
看见我不会不舒服的生物
who didn't get uncomfortable when he was around me.
记得我们常常玩得好开心
I remember we used to have this great game we played together.
我们玩的是“球”
It was called "ball."
把球扔出去，它捡回来？
You mean, you'd throw the ball, and he'd go fetch it?
这样也好玩
That would've worked, too.
它后来怎样了？
What happened to him?
死了
He died.
17年了
Seventeen years ago.
以后再也没有谁跟我一起住了
He was the last person I ever lived with.
你伤心了？
Were you sad?
是的
Yeah.
你哭了吗？
Did you cry?
哭了
Yes.
你还要自杀吗？
Are you still gonna kill yourself?
不知道
本.
Ben.
I don't know.
不自杀的话，我这狗可以送你
Well, if you don't kill yourself, you can have my puppy.
波德维尔先生？
Hello? Mr. Bodewell?
-妈妈，他怎么了？ -我也不知道
- Mom, what happened to him? - I don't know, honey.
波德维尔先生？爸爸？
Mr. Bodewell? Dad?
杰森？
Jason? Jason?
来了
Yes?
-爸爸! -爸爸!
- Dad! - Dad!
波德维尔先生!
Mr. Bodewell!
-杰森，没事吧？ -我们都没事
- Jason, are you okay? - Yeah, I think we're okay.
-这是我的小狗 -真可爱
- This is my puppy. - He's a nice one.
圣诞快乐!
Merry Christmas.
我宣布，西弗一家可以打开礼物了
And now it's time for the opening of the Seaver family Christmas-Eve presents.
记住，这些礼物不是我买的
Oh, now, remember, I didn't buy any of these presents...
不喜欢可不能怪我
so if you don't like your present, it's not my fault.
-波德维尔 -对不起，这样吧
- Walter. - Oh, I'm sorry. Oh, here.
-嗯 -好多了
- Yeah. - Better. Better.
这是凯罗的，这是麦克的
Okay, this one's for Carol. This one's for Mike.
“亲爱的麦克，这是我家3代的传统”
"Dear Mike, this has been handed down in our family...
“送给每个到达成年的男子”
"for three generations to each man as he comes of age."
刮胡刀？咱俩换吧
A razor. I think we better switch.
什么？要破坏传统？
What, and break family tradition?
这是妈妈的礼物.
Now one for Mom...
-还有.. -谢谢
- and... - Oh, thank you.
好啊
-爸爸的 -谢谢
...one for Dad. - Oh, thank you. Thank you.
-“烹调技术突飞猛进” -是的
All right.
- "Most Improved Cook of the Year." - Yes.
那圣诞晚餐我来下厨吧
That mean you all want me to make Christmas dinner?
-不用了，谢谢 -宝贝，没事
- No, thanks. - It's okay, sweetheart.
-谢谢你 -爱你
- Thanks anyway. - We love you.
正是
这就是让我等了一天的浪漫大礼？
Is this the exciting and romantic gift I've been waiting all day for?
That's the one.
来，我告诉你怎么用
Here, let me show you how it works.
让我瞧瞧
Let's see here.
杰森，真漂亮 亲爱的，谢谢
Oh, Jason, they're beautiful. Thank you, honey.
-谢谢 -看上去像真的一样
- Thank you. - They look real, don't they?
什么意思？假的？
What do you mean, aren't they real?
本，对不起，你没有礼物了
Ben, I'm so sorry. There's no gift for you.
想要回小狗吗？
Do you want Nick back?
不，归你了
No, Walter, he's yours.
波德维尔，去翻翻袋子 说不定有本的礼物
Walter, why don't you check the bag? Maybe Santa left something for Ben.
怎么不去看看呢？
-对 -不，口袋空了
- Yeah. - No, it's empty.
-说不定有呢 -是啊
Well, why don't you check it anyway?
袋子已经空了，所有的牛肉已经.
- There might be something there. - Yeah.
No, really, it's empty. See, we put the ground beef in the freezer...
波德维尔，去看看吧
Walter, check the bag.
-好吧 -我来拿着
- Oh, okay. Here. - Yes, I'll take him. Okay.
-好的 -哇!
- There you go. - Oh, wow!
真有一份礼物
There is a present for Ben.
-是吗？ -是啊
- There is? - Yeah.
-给我的小狗 -对
- Wow, a puppy for me. - Yeah.
跟你的一模一样
He looks just like Nick.
真谢谢你们
Well, thank you, all of you, for everything.
小狗真漂亮
Nick is beautiful.
我的小狗也是，它叫做波德维尔
So is my puppy. I think I'll name her Walter.
-圣诞快乐 -圣诞快乐
- Merry Christmas. - Merry Christmas.
波德维尔，咱留点吃的给圣诞老人
Well, Walter, we'll just leave this little snack for Santa Claus...
不是说我相信圣诞老人
which is not to say that I believe in Santa Claus...
但俗语说，宁可信其有.
but in life, Walter, you'll find it pays to hedge your bets.
呵呵，圣诞快乐!
Ho! Ho! Ho! Merry Christmas!
[zeroxia@gmail.com] 2006.03.12